Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是斯科特-曼利
In the last week we have found out that NASA are going back to Venus
在上周 我们发现美国宇航局将重返金星
with not one but two missions.
不是一项而是两项任务
So these are two missions are selected from the latest batch of Discovery program candidates.
因此 这两项任务是从最新一批发现计划候选人中挑选出来的
They had four and the two that were going to Venus were the ones that were picked
他们有四个任务 而这两个要去金星的任务是被选中的
and unfortunately this does mean that we are not going to be flying by Triton anytime soon.
不幸的是 这确实意味着我们不会在短期内飞过海卫一
And we're not going to be sending an explorer to look at the volcanoes of Io
我们也不会派一个探险家去看木卫二的火山
but we are going to be sending an atmosphere probe and lander in the form of DAVINCI+
但我们将派出一个大气层探测器和登陆器 即DAVINCI+
and an orbiter which will map the planet in the form of VERITAS.
和一个轨道器 它将以VERITAS的形式绘制该行星的地图
Now I have talked in the past about various ways of exploring the surface of Venus long term.
现在我在过去谈到了长期探索金星表面的各种方法
Things like clockwork rovers or high temperature semiconductors.
诸如发条漫游器或高温半导体
But neither of these things are on display here.
但是这些东西都没有在这里展示
This is two missions which are very much similar to older missions
这是两项与旧的任务非常相似的任务
albeit with 30 plus years of technological advancement.
尽管有30多年的技术进步
The last time NASA sent a spacecraft to Venus was Magellan in 1989
美国宇航局上一次向金星发送航天器是1989年的麦哲伦号
and that spacecraft was actually mostly built from spare parts.
而那个航天器实际上大部分是用零部件制造的
The DAVINCI lander is going to be the first lander to go to Venus since Vega in the mid 1980s.
DAVINCI登陆器将是自20世纪80年代中期织女星以来第一个前往金星的登陆器
The DAVINCI+ descent probe will only return data for a couple of hours
DAVINCI+下降探测器将只返回几个小时的数据
but the technology will have moved on a whole lot
但技术将有很大的进步
and there's a lot of questions that this can answer in that very limited time span.
而且在这个非常有限的时间跨度内 有很多问题可以回答
I often like to talk about
我经常喜欢谈及
how the surface of Venus is one of the most inhospitable locations in the solar system.
金星的表面是太阳系中最荒凉的地方之一
The surface pressure is about 93 atmospheres.
表面压力约为93个大气压
The temperature is hot enough to melt lead.
温度高到足以融化铅
It is acidic.
它是酸性的
It is choking.
它令人窒息
It will asphyxiate you. You do not want to go there.
它将使你窒息 你不会想去那里
And yet many people didn't realize how what kind of hell whole Venus was until like the start of the space age.
然而许多人没有意识到整个金星是怎样的一个地狱 直到像太空时代的开始
My dad had a bunch of books I remember him showing me things that he had when he was a child.
我爸爸有一堆书 我记得他给我看他小时候的东西
And it talked about what could be under the clouds of Venus.
它谈到了金星云层下可能存在的东西
Telescopes couldn't see under it
望远镜无法看到它的下面
and with nothing to see there people's imaginations ran wild
由于没有东西可看 人们的想象力就很丰富了
and they imagined crazy things like jungles with dinosaurs that we could go and hunt.
他们想象出一些疯狂的事情 比如有恐龙的丛林 我们可以去狩猎
Unfortunately those clouds on Venus are sulfuric acid
不幸的是 金星上的那些云层是硫酸
and yet they contain the majority of the water that is left on Venus.
但它们却包含了金星上所剩的大部分水
It's now known that Venus was very much wet in its distant history
现在已经知道 金星在其遥远的历史上是非常潮湿的
and you might wonder how could we know what Venus was like in the past.
你可能会问 我们怎么能知道金星在过去是什么样子呢？
And of course the answer is science.
当然 答案是科学
In 1978 a spacecraft was launched called the Pioneer Multiprobe.
1978年 一个名为 "先锋多探测器 "的航天器被发射出去
It flew past Venus and it dropped a number of probes in
它飞过金星 在金星上投放了一些探测器
and one large probe contained a mass spectrometer.
其中一个大型探测器包含一个质谱仪
As it descended through the atmosphere it was sampling the atmosphere
当它在大气层中下降时 它对大气层进行采样
and basically measuring the atomic masses of the molecules and atoms that it was finding there.
并基本上测量它在那里发现的分子和原子的原子质量
And the analysis of this showed that there was an excessive amount of deuterium compared to hydrogen.
分析结果显示 与氢相比 氘的数量过多
So hydrogen has an isotope called deuterium that has an extra neutron and it's twice as heavy.
因此 氢有一种叫做氘的同位素 它有一个额外的中子 它的重量是氢的两倍
Now on earth one in every seven thousand hydrogen atoms is actually a heavier deuterium atom
现在在地球上 每七千个氢原子中就有一个实际上是更重的氘原子
but on Venus it's one in seventy and that is about a hundred times greater.
但在金星上 它是七十分之一 这大约是一百倍
And the reason for this is that over time water evaporated from Venus.
其原因是 随着时间的推移 金星上的水蒸发了
And the lighter hydrogen atoms escaped more easily
而较轻的氢原子更容易逃脱
leaving behind the heavier deuterium atoms.
留下了较重的氘原子
So if we assume that Venus formed from roughly the same material as earth
因此 如果我们假设金星是由与地球大致相同的物质形成的
then you would expect the ratios of hydrogen deuterium to be the same
那么你会期望氢氘的比例是相同的
but since Venus has 100 times more deuterium
但是 由于金星的氘多出100倍
you have to imagine at some point it had 100 times more regular hydrogen
你必须想象在某些时候它有100倍的常规氢气
and therefore at least 100 times more water in the past.
并因此在过去至少有100倍的水
And that is of course a lower estimate assuming that no deuterium at all escapes.
而这当然是一个较低的估计 假设根本就没有氘逃逸
And the lack of water and Venus can also be responsible for its really thick atmosphere.
而水的缺乏和金星也可能是其真正的厚重大气的原因
On earth carbon dioxide and other gases that come up from volcanoes
在地球上 二氧化碳和其他气体从火山中喷出
they go through various processes and end up getting incorporated into rocks
它们经历了各种过程 最终被纳入岩石中
and a lot of these processes involve water.
而这些过程中很多都涉及到水
But if you take the water out of the system these gases get stuck in the atmosphere.
但是如果你把水从系统中拿出来 这些气体就会卡在大气中
They don't get deposited into rocks.
它们不会沉积到岩石中
And so you end up with an atmosphere that gets thicker and thicker and thicker
因此 你最终会有一个越来越厚的大气层 越来越厚 越来越厚
until you get the modern day hellhole that is Venus.
直到你得到现代的金星这个地狱般的地方
So we can imagine that DAVINCI+ will do this a whole lot better than the Pioneer probes.
因此 我们可以想象 DAVINCI+将比先锋号探测器在这方面做得更好
I mean the Pioneer probes were obviously great
我的意思是 先锋号探测器显然是伟大的
but the data bandwidth they used for mass spectrometer was 40 bits per second.
但他们用于质谱仪的数据带宽是每秒40比特
Nowadays we'll do a lot better.
现在我们会做得更好
The other thing it's going to do is take pictures a lot of pictures.
它要做的另一件事是拍照 拍大量的照片
You know that there's less than 10 pictures of the surface of Venus all taken by the Venera landers
你知道有不到10张金星表面的照片都是由Venera登陆器拍摄的
and they were all very similar in design.
而且它们在设计上都非常相似
They had a spherical pressure vessel.
他们有一个球形的压力容器
They have this landing ring with the shock absorbers.
他们有这个带有减震器的着陆环
Above that there's this disc.
在那上面有这个圆盘
And that is the parachute.
这就是降落伞
They didn't have a regular parachute.
他们没有一个普通的降落伞
They just needed this disc to decelerate them because the atmosphere is so thick.
他们只是需要这个圆盘来使他们减速 因为大气层太厚了
And then above that is this sort of circular spiral antenna.
然后上面是这种圆形的螺旋形天线
Venera 11 and 12 both carry colored cameras.
维纳拉11号和12号都携带有彩色相机
But the lens caps failed to separate so these images are from Venera 13 and 14.
但镜头盖未能分离 所以这些图像是来自Venera 13和14
So DAVINCI+ on its way down will be capturing imagery
因此 DAVINCI+在其下行途中将捕捉到图像
giving us good resolutions all the way down to impact.
给我们提供良好的分辨率 一直到撞击
But obviously this is only off a very small section of the surface.
但显然这只是表面的一个很小的部分
If you want to look at a global thing you need an orbiter.
如果你想看一个全球的东西 你需要一个轨道器
And we've been mapping Venus with orbiters for a very long time.
而我们用轨道飞行器绘制金星地图已经有很长一段时间了
Again this is from Pioneer.
这也是来自先锋号
it used synthetic aperture radar to give us a topographical map in the late 1970s.
它使用合成孔径雷达在1970年代末为我们提供了一张地形图
Several of the Venera probes followed up and did their own version
一些维纳号探测器跟进并做了他们自己的版本
but the sort of definitive map that is used for everything
但这种确定的地图被用于所有的事情
including those visualizations I used earlier for space engine was Magellan
包括我先前用于空间引擎的那些视觉化的地图是麦哲伦的
And this was the last mission that NASA sent to Venus
这是美国航空航天局派往金星的最后一次任务
Actually that's not true
事实上 这并不是真的
because several NASA missions have flown past Venus
因为美国宇航局的一些任务已经飞过了金星
because it's a great place to get a gravity assist from.
因为它是一个可以获得重力辅助的好地方
Galileo went there.
伽利略号去了那里
Cassini went there.
卡西尼号去了那里
But Magellan that launched from the Space Shuttle
但是从航天飞机上发射的麦哲伦号
it was the first interplanetary spacecraft to launch from the Space Shuttle.
它是第一个从航天飞机上发射的行星际航天器
And it spent several years mapping the surface using SAR.
它花了几年时间 用合成孔径雷达绘制表面
Now I find this to be a fascinating mission because it will in part.
现在我发现这是一个迷人的任务 因为它将在一定程度上
Because it's built from a bunch of pieces that were designed for other spacecraft.
因为它是由一堆为其他航天器设计的部件建成的
The main bus is from a Voyager.
主总线是来自旅行者号
That antenna is designed for Voyager. The thrusters are Voyager.
那个天线是为旅行者号设计的 推进器是旅行者号的
Then there's a lot of electronics, avionics, attitude control systems that were for the Galileo spacecraft.
然后有很多电子、航空电子设备、姿态控制系统是为伽利略号飞船设计的
So thanks to the work of Magellan we have maps of Venus that are good to about 100 meter resolution.
因此 由于麦哲伦号的工作 我们有了金星的地图 其分辨率可以达到100米左右
That means you can go to google maps
这意味着你可以去谷歌地图
and look at a map of Venus with a bunch of the terrain already laid out for you.
并查看金星的地图 上面已经为你铺设了大量的地形
It's great although it looks decidedly 2D.
这很好 尽管它看起来是2D的
If you really want to fly over Venus I highly recommend you get Space Engine.
如果你真的想飞越金星 我强烈建议你购买太空引擎
And you can turn off the clouds if you like or not.
而且你可以关闭云层 如果你喜欢或不喜欢
Or you can just fly anywhere in the solar system or the entire universe
或者你可以在太阳系或整个宇宙的任何地方飞行
because space engine is pretty amazing.
因为太空引擎是相当惊人的
So how is VERITAS going to improve on this.
那么VERITAS是如何在此基础上进行改进的
Well its main instrument is VISAR, the Venus Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar.
嗯 它的主要仪器是VISAR 金星干涉合成孔径雷达
It's basically a new better synthetic aperture radar.
它基本上是一个新的更好的合成孔径雷达
It is going to perform surface scans off the whole globe over its mission.
它将在其任务期间对整个地球进行表面扫描
It's going to measure pixel accuracy to about 15 meters with five meter vertical resolution.
它将测量的像素精度约为15米 垂直分辨率为5米
And because it's going to visit some areas multiple times
因为它将多次访问一些地区
they'll be able to do compare each area via interferometry.
他们将能够通过干涉测量法来比较每个区域
That's where they can actually see how things have changed within a region.
这就是他们可以实际看到一个区域内事物的变化情况
And that is going to be accurate to about 0.2 centimeters 2 millimeters.
而这将精确到大约0.2厘米2毫米
And the reason they want this stunning accuracy is
而他们之所以希望有这样惊人的精确度
because they want to see if Venus is still geologically active.
因为他们想看看金星是否仍有地质活动
They want to see if there are active deformation zones
他们想看看是否有活跃的变形区
because we don't know whether the surface of Venus was formed a long time ago and is pretty much dead
因为我们不知道金星的表面是在很久以前形成的 而且几乎是死的
or whether there is active tectonics going on.
或者是否有活跃的构造在进行
One of the interesting things about Venus is there are these areas called Tesserae
关于金星的一个有趣的事情是 有这些被称为魔方的区域
which we think may actually be the Venusian equivalent of continents like we're formed on earth
我们认为它实际上可能相当于金星上的大陆 就像我们在地球上形成的那样
but in the absence of water
但在没有水的情况下
is these being formed by the same mechanic or is there something else going on.
这些是由相同的机械形成的 还是有其他的事情发生
A second instrument carried is the Venus emissivity mapper
携带的第二个仪器是金星发射率测绘仪
and this is a basically a thermal imaging spectrometer.
这基本上是一个热成像光谱仪
It's going to look through the clouds.
它将透过云层来观察
They've carefully chosen specific band passes
他们精心选择了特定的波段通道
where the infrared light passes through the clouds with less interference.
红外线穿过云层的地方 干扰较少
And basically they'll be able to sample areas of the surface
基本上 他们将能够对表面的区域进行采样
and view them in multiple infrared wave bands
并在多个红外波段中观察它们
and what they're looking for is the light being emitted by the surface because it's hot.
他们正在寻找的是由表面发出的光 因为它很热
And well you might imagine the surface of Venus is being kept at a pretty constant temperature
你可以想象 金星的表面被保持在一个相当稳定的温度下
due to like the temperature of Venus being very heavily controlled by that thick atmosphere
由于金星的温度被那厚厚的大气层控制得很厉害
there will be differences in how the surface emits.
表面的发光方式会有差异
And that will tell you the materials it's made of.
而这将告诉你它是由什么材料制成的
It'll give you clues to the ground structure
它将给你关于地面结构的线索
and so it may actually be possible to see differences
因此 实际上有可能看到相对较新的熔岩流和天气之间的差异
between relatively recent lava flows and weathered lava flows
相对较新的熔岩流和风化的熔岩流之间的差异
that have been exposed to the atmosphere over time.
随着时间的推移暴露在大气中
It's a multi-band instrument operating at about one micrometer.
这是一个多波段的仪器 工作在大约一微米的位置
From the six bands they're going to use
从他们将要使用的六个波段中
it will allow them to distinguish certain mineralogy differences.
它将使他们能够区分某些矿物学差异
And obviously the whole thing is going to be operating primarily on the night side of Venus
很明显 整个仪器将主要在金星的夜间一侧运行
because you don't want to contaminate your light with well light from the sun.
因为你不想用来自太阳的光污染你的光线
And finally a lot of consideration is being given to how it communicates with the deep space network
最后 大量的考虑是它如何与深空网络进行沟通
because not only will it be sending data
因为它不仅要发送数据
but they will be very carefully measuring the doppler shifts when they are doing these communication sessions.
而且他们将非常仔细地测量多普勒位移 当他们进行这些通信会议时
Because they're going to use that as a reference point for measuring changes in spacecraft's velocity
因为他们将使用它作为一个参考点来测量航天器的速度变化
And therefore try to find gravitational features.
因此试图找到引力特征
Perhaps sub-surface structure which hasn't been visible via other methods.
也许是通过其他方法无法看到的地表下结构
So VERITAS will fly about the end of the decade
所以VERITAS将在本世纪末飞行
and that will be 70 years since the first mission to successfully fly by Venus.
而那将是自第一次成功飞越金星的任务以来的70年
Mariner 2 also built by the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
水手2号也是由喷气推进实验室建造的
Humanity has sent dozens of missions to Venus over the decades.
几十年来 人类已经向金星派出了几十次任务
And yet we still don't have a good answer for whether Venus is a geologically active world
然而 对于金星是否是一个地质活跃的世界 我们仍然没有一个好的答案
or whether its interior is as quiet as its surface is lifeless.
或者它的内部是否像它的表面一样安静 没有生命
I'm scott manley. Fly safe.
我是斯科特-曼利 飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]